# **Abby Smith**

Arvada, Colorado | 720-398-0660 | abby.e.smith.85@gmail.com LinkedIn | Github | Blog

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full stack software engineer with experience in Python with Flask and JavaScript based programming and with 11 years experience in secondary math education. Possess the ability to pick up new skills quickly through independent study and group collaboration. Experienced in client communication and project management in fast paced environments.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Python with Flask, SQL, JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, Github, ChartJS, Next.JS

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

# Graphr - Github | Demo

Secondary math student facing app designed to allow students to digitally complete traditional graphing homework.

- Utilized JavaScript, React, Python, Flask and ChartJS to create an interactive graphing application
- Stores user data with SQLAlchemy
- Users creates accounts with encrypted password with Bcrypt
- EmailJS is integrated to allow students to contact their instructor without leaving the site

# Algebra Review Site - Github | Demo

High school algebra review website with resources available for students to review, monitor their progress and complete a self grading practice quiz.

- Utilized JavaScript and React to create interactive features including learning logs and marking skills as mastered
- Imports React, useEffect, useState and useCollapse
- Imported Popup to allow for information to expand when user clicked
- Designed a self grading practice quiz and wrote a how to blog post to share with the community

# The Quest for the Holy Grail - Github | Demo

CLI game that sends users on three challenges to win a seat at King Arthor's Round Table

- Stored data using SQLAlchemy tables to show all users who successfully completed the game and their score
- Utilized Python to create an interactive command line
- Included sound and color to the CLI to enhance usability and created a blog post to share with the community
- Routes are used to increase usability of the app
- Implemented a user login and password system

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Jeffco Public Schools

Arvada, Colorado 08/2015 - 07/2022

Math Teacher / EdTech Liaison

- Designed and implemented secondary math curriculums catering to students with diverse learning needs.
- Facilitated instructional technology support through one on one mentoring, group sessions and conference presentations to professionals to facilitate effective use of educational technology.
- Developed and utilized data collection methods to analyze student performance to inform teaching methodologies.
- Lead the student JeffCo Cyber Crew class in chromebook repair and school based IT support.

## Edison Learning and LearningMate

Remote

Subject Matter Expert (Contract)

08/2022 - 02/2023

- Wrote and edited digital Geometry curriculum for students in a non-traditional school environment.
- Collaborated with software engineers to increase the end user experience through interactive lesson components.
- Designed student projects to measure student learning by connecting the math curriculum to the real world.

## **EDUCATION**

**Flatiron School** 

Denver, Colorado

Full Stack Web Development, Python with Flask and JavaScript program

01/2023 - 05/2023

**Radford University** 

Radford, Virginia

Bachelor of Science (BS), Mathematics Masters in Education (MEdu), Secondary Math Education 05/2011

07/2015